<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>LIFT Renewal Ministries</title>
    <link>http://liftrenewal.org</link>
    <pubDate>Fri, 04 Sep 2015 10:09:14 -0700</pubDate>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lectionary Reading Week</title>
      <link>http://liftrenewal.org/events/lectionary-reading-week</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Sep 2015 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <author>Jeremy Ricketts</author>
      <guid>http://liftrenewal.org/events/lectionary-reading-week</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Spend a dedicated week with your colleagues in ministry reading through all the Gospel passages for the coming year, crafting a plan for your preaching ministry in the 2015-16 Lectionary Year. The Southern California session is moving this year to beautiful &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Oak Glen in the heart of Apple Country&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, with a new &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;reduced&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; registration cost, too! &lt;a href=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/roblyimages/accounts/4012/original/1428354451786-ez3uwnpgd49xjemi-70e6c02d4bdfff49fe743725ebb18f8b.pdf&quot;&gt;All you need to know and register is right here!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clergy Class Meetings for September</title>
      <link>http://liftrenewal.org/events/clergy-class-meetings-september-2015</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2015 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <author>Jeremy Ricketts</author>
      <guid>http://liftrenewal.org/events/clergy-class-meetings-september-2015</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Every Wednesday morning at 10:30am, Pastors from churches in the Inland Empire gather for a traditional &lt;strong&gt;Wesleyan Class Meeting&lt;/strong&gt;. SEPTEMBER Class Meetings ALL clergy are welcome. Location changes monthly. Contact LIFT for more information. (562)789-0880&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ministry in Ghana</title>
      <link>http://liftrenewal.org/events/ministry-in-ghana</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Aug 2015 11:08:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <author>Jeremy Ricketts</author>
      <guid>http://liftrenewal.org/events/ministry-in-ghana</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A Team of 6 clergy and laypersons will travel to Accra, Ghana, in West Africa, this summer for a third mission trip to strengthen local church leaders in disciple-making. Your prayers are welcomed as they travel and serve! &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The past 2 years have focused on the &amp;ldquo;Big 5&amp;rdquo; of discipleship and building a Discipling Network which reaches out beyond the walls of the church. Following up on those previous seminars, LIFT this year will have conversation with a core group of leaders to encourage them forward in their efforts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;LIFT Team members will also take part in evening Revival Worship services and preach in local congregations on Sunday morning. A visit to the &lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;LIFT Renewal Center&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt; currently under construction will be included, to view the progress of this special project and pray with the construction team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;The LIFT Mission Team members:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rev. William Johnson &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dr. Bob Denham &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rev. Tonya Harris &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rev. Tom Rothhaar &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;David Nesamony &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Judy Gillham &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mission dates are: August 11 through 22, 2015.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your support for this work is greatly appreciated!  Prayer sustains the Team, and financial support helps with the cost of supplies. There is also an opportunity to support the building of the LIFT Renewal Center. By clicking on the &lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;Donate&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt; button you may make a gift to LIFT Ministries, and indicate how you would like your gift to be applied.  Thank-You! &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;Thou shalt decree a thing, and it shall be established unto thee; and the light shall shine upon thy ways.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;   Job 22:28&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a Place for Renewal</title>
      <link>http://liftrenewal.org/blog/building-a-place-for-renewal</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jun 2015 16:30:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <author>Jeremy Ricketts</author>
      <guid>http://liftrenewal.org/blog/building-a-place-for-renewal</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;LIFT Ministries&lt;/strong&gt;, in partnership with LIFT in Ghana, is supporting the creation of the &lt;strong&gt;LIFT Renewal Center&lt;/strong&gt;! &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Imagine&amp;hellip;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A place for Spiritual Retreat&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A place for Leadership Training&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A place for Visiting Missionaries&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A place to host the Walk to Emmaus&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the U.S. we are blessed with the availability of 
comfortable, affordable facilities. 
But the Methodist Church in Ghana has very limited facilities for pastors and laypersons to take retreat 
for spiritual renewal,apart from expensive hotels.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Together we can make this happen - We are blessed to be a blessing!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;LIFT Ministries is raising money in order to build this facility 
which will be used for all these purposes as well 
as hosting Walk to Emmaus weekends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thus far, LIFT has raised $5,000 to build the Center ! 
The remaining cost to complete the construction 
is approximately $60,000.
You can support this vital project by making a 
tax-deductible gift to LIFT Ministries in any amount.   &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Visit &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.LiftRenewal.org&quot;&gt;www.LiftRenewal.org&lt;/a&gt; and click &amp;ldquo;Donate&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Thank-You!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Renewal Center in Ghana</title>
      <link>http://liftrenewal.org/events/renewal-center-in-ghana</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jun 2015 12:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <author>Jeremy Ricketts</author>
      <guid>http://liftrenewal.org/events/renewal-center-in-ghana</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;LIFT Ministries&lt;/strong&gt;, in partnership with LIFT in Ghana,is supporting the creation of the &lt;strong&gt;LIFT Renewal Center&lt;/strong&gt;! &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Imagine&amp;hellip;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A place for Spiritual Retreat&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A place for Leadership Training&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A place for Visiting Missionaries&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A place to host the Walk to Emmaus&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the U.S. we are blessed with the availability of 
comfortable, affordable facilities. 
But the Methodist Church in Ghana has very limited facilities for pastors and laypersons to take retreat 
for spiritual renewal,apart from expensive hotels.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Together we can make this happen - We are blessed to be a blessing!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;LIFT Ministries is raising money in order to build this facility 
which will be used for all these purposes as well 
as hosting Walk to Emmaus weekends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thus far, LIFT has raised $5,000 to build the Center ! 
The remaining cost to complete the construction 
is approximately $60,000.
You can support this vital project by making a 
tax-deductible gift to LIFT Ministries in any amount.   &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Visit &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.LiftRenewal.org&quot;&gt;www.LiftRenewal.org&lt;/a&gt; and click &amp;ldquo;Donate&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Thank-You!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prayer Walk at University UMC</title>
      <link>http://liftrenewal.org/events/prayer-walk-at-university-umc</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jun 2015 09:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <author>Jeremy Ricketts</author>
      <guid>http://liftrenewal.org/events/prayer-walk-at-university-umc</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Saturday,June 13,is the next LIFT Prayer Walk in the Inland Empire at University United Methodist Church in Redlands. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All are welcome! On the 2nd Saturday of each month we start out from a different church in the Inland Empire in order to cover our communities with Prayer, and Listen to God. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ll have a brief time of worship and prayer together,
then walk and pray silently through the community.&lt;br&gt;
Open to EVERYONE - you don&amp;rsquo;t need to be an expert &amp;lsquo;pray-er&amp;rsquo;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And this is the confidence that we have toward him, that if we ask anything according to his will he hears us. 1 John 5:14&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LIFT Renewal Weekend</title>
      <link>http://liftrenewal.org/events/lift-renewal-weekend</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 May 2015 14:11:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <author>Jeremy Ricketts</author>
      <guid>http://liftrenewal.org/events/lift-renewal-weekend</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Seminar - The Ministry of the Church Office</title>
      <link>http://liftrenewal.org/events/ministry-of-the-church-office</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Apr 2015 09:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <author>Jeremy Ricketts</author>
      <guid>http://liftrenewal.org/events/ministry-of-the-church-office</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;LIFT Ministries&lt;/strong&gt; presents a new Seminar designed to strengthen,encourage,and equip those persons entrusted with running the church office and assisting the Pastor &amp;ndash; &lt;strong&gt;Administrative Assistants, Office Managers, Church Secretaries&lt;/strong&gt;, etc. This is a very important ministry to which God calls us in order to use our spiritual gifts to their fullest to give glory to God and strengthen the Body of Christ.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You are invited to spend a day away from the office to worship, engage in prayer and Bible study together,and then take a good look at the responsibilities and challenges of your job through the lens of Ministry.  Understanding that church administration is not merely a set of tasks on a job description, LIFT is offering an opportunity for participants to indeed embrace their roles as ministry,identify a variety of spiritual and practical resources available to them, and be renewed as they return to their workplace. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“The Ministry of the Church Office&amp;quot;&lt;/strong&gt; is facilitated by &lt;strong&gt;Judy Gillham&lt;/strong&gt;, herself a veteran of church office administration, and currently serves as the Ministries Coordinator for LIFT Ministries. She is a woman of deep prayer and great faith, who believes that we are charged with working “as unto the Lord” in all things. Judy brings experience, compassion, and her sense of humor to this seminar and is eager to share this special day with her colleagues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Date&lt;/strong&gt;: Tuesday, April 28, 2015 &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Time&lt;/strong&gt;: 9:00am to 2:00pm-Lunch is Included! &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cost&lt;/strong&gt;: $25 per Person&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/roblyimages/accounts/4012/original/1427137603088-c248g8o0mhg2e29-82a97829a2298c3458beb8ef98340f40.pdf&quot;&gt;Click Here to download and print the Registration Form&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Send completed form no later than April 22.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Contact Judy Gillham with your questions at (562) 789-0880&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prayer Walking</title>
      <link>http://liftrenewal.org/events/prayer-walking-9-12-2015</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Apr 2015 09:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <author>Jeremy Ricketts</author>
      <guid>http://liftrenewal.org/events/prayer-walking-9-12-2015</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Cover the Inland Empire with Prayer&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Every 2nd Saturday of the month&lt;/em&gt;, LIFT Ministries goes Prayer Walking in the community surrounding the church. There is time for worship and prayer together, then, in small groups, we walk through the neighborhood to listen to God and lift up the community in prayer. Come be a blessing. Come bring light and peace into the world!  See you at HIGHLAND UMC in San Bernardino! Gather at 9am in the Sanctuary.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Board of Directors Annual Meeting</title>
      <link>http://liftrenewal.org/events/board-of-directors-annual-meeting</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Mar 2015 09:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <author>Jeremy Ricketts</author>
      <guid>http://liftrenewal.org/events/board-of-directors-annual-meeting</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Board of Directors of LIFT Renewal Ministries will gather for their Annual Meeting at the LIFT Offices in Uptown Whittier.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ghana Mission Meeting</title>
      <link>http://liftrenewal.org/events/ghana-mission-meeting</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Mar 2015 10:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <author>Jeremy Ricketts</author>
      <guid>http://liftrenewal.org/events/ghana-mission-meeting</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;By God&amp;rsquo;s grace, LIFT will again organize a Team to serve in Ghana this summer. If you would like to learn about this mission and be considered for the Team, you&amp;rsquo;re invited to attend an information meeting at the LIFT Ministries office on &lt;strong&gt;Saturday, March 7th at 10am.&lt;/strong&gt;. If you have any questions ahead of time, please call Judy Gillham, Ministry Coordinator, at &lt;strong&gt;(562) 789-0880, or click the &amp;ldquo;Contact&amp;rdquo; tab to email LIFT&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inland Empire Prayer Walking</title>
      <link>http://liftrenewal.org/events/inland-empire-prayer-walking</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2015 09:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <author>Jeremy Ricketts</author>
      <guid>http://liftrenewal.org/events/inland-empire-prayer-walking</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Saturday - February 14 - is the next LIFT Prayer Walk in the St. Paul&amp;rsquo;s United Methodist Church in San Bernardino. On the 2nd Saturday of each month we start out from a different church in the Inland Empire area in order to cover our communities with Prayer and Listen to God.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All are welcome! Meet at St. Paul&amp;rsquo;s UMC at 9am. We’ll have a brief time of worship and prayer together, then form small groups to walk and pray silently through the community. A couple people will be asked to remain in the Sanctuary to keep vigil while we walk, interceding for the walkers. After about 45 minutes or so, we’ll return to the church to share what God was showing us, then pray, and return home. Come and be a blessing in the community!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And this is the confidence that we have toward him, that if we ask anything according to his will he hears us. 1 John 5:14&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Christmas Day</title>
      <link>http://liftrenewal.org/events/christmas-day</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2014 16:33:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <author>Jeremy Ricketts</author>
      <guid>http://liftrenewal.org/events/christmas-day</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Shouldn&amp;rsquo;t show!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Distinguishing Birthmark</title>
      <link>http://liftrenewal.org/blog/a-distinguishing-birthmark</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2014 15:59:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <author>Jeremy Ricketts</author>
      <guid>http://liftrenewal.org/blog/a-distinguishing-birthmark</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Beloved, let us love one another, said the author of 1 John, for God is love. Likewise Paul in his triumphant hymn to the Corinthian church: faith, hope, and love abide, these three, and the greatest of these is love. For Christians, no less than any others, love is an essential part of the human experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But love is a tricky thing, full of delight and hurt, aspiration and risk all at the same time. Because every loving heart can be wounded, because every love-inspired promise can be broken, because every loving friendship can be severed, there lies at the heart of true Christian community the essential need for forgiveness. Indeed, if the foundation of the church is God’s grace, then the currency with which we conduct our everyday affairs is forgiveness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Forgiveness originates in Jesus Christ, and grows in our hearts by his word, and bears fruit in our lives by shaping our will and guiding our actions. Before and behind us, and all along the path to God’s shalom we find forgiveness. Unforgiveness, on the other hand, prevents us from peace. It keeps us from sharing the whole nature of God. It weighs us down with uncertainty and mistrust and bitterness, sours our expression with cynicism and becomes a barrier in our path to God.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At some point in time each of us will suffer an injury at the hand of love which seems too big to let go, too important to leave out of our autobiography. But in Matthew’s gospel Jesus urges us to release such injuries and remember them no more. We are invited to see our wounds in the light of the Cross of Christ, to witness the power of the resurrection, and to remember: that our Christian community originates in the forgiveness of Christ, and is sustained in our forgiveness of one another.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jesus bids us rise above the shifting wind of our emotions and feelings. Forgiveness is meant to be a daily practice&amp;hellip; a way of life&amp;hellip; distinguishing mark of our new birth in Christ Jesus.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>God at Work Within Us</title>
      <link>http://liftrenewal.org/blog/god-at-work-within-us</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2014 16:02:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <author>Jeremy Ricketts</author>
      <guid>http://liftrenewal.org/blog/god-at-work-within-us</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In all of history, there has never been a king like Jesus. He holds no earthly crown or scepter. He covets no earthly throne or dominion. He kneels as a servant, welcomes children, touches the untouchable, and mingles with the outcasts. He came not be served, but to serve, and in his life provided the model for faithfulness to which every follower of his must forever aspire.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of his followers was Paul, the “Apostle to the Gentiles”. Over the course of his ministry, Paul suffered many hardships and much persecution for the privilege of preaching the Gospel. Ultimately he was arrested and sent to Rome, where he became a martyr for the faith. It was while under arrest on his way to Rome that the church in Philippi expressed their deep love and concern for Paul, and their sense of hopelessness and grief at his circumstances.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Paul’s response—the Letter to Philippi we find in scripture—is a ringing testimonial to the faithfulness of Christ over his church, and the confidence we can have in Christ no matter our circumstances. Paul reminds the church that as individual believers, we come to Christ in profoundly personal ways…but our deeply personal faith is never private. For through our baptism we are incorporated into the Body of Christ, and through the promised Holy Spirit we are all being knit together so that our gifts and graces work in concert together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thus we bear one another’s burdens, rejoice in one another’s victories, and bolster one another in times of powerlessness and in the face of death. All of this is not by our own strength; it is the work of Christ in us and through us. Christ himself is transforming the world, having first redeemed in his own life and death. As we become like him—have his mind among us—he is completing his transforming work in our lives.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>It’s the Little Things</title>
      <link>http://liftrenewal.org/blog/its-the-little-things</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2014 16:32:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <author>Jeremy Ricketts</author>
      <guid>http://liftrenewal.org/blog/its-the-little-things</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There is an old hymn of our faith which begins with these words: Once to every man and nation, comes the moment to decide, In the strife of truth with falsehood, for the good or evil side;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The hymn writer is partially right…it is rare that a heroic choice between truth and falsehood or good and evil is suddenly and clearly required. And in those moments of crisis or judgment, when the dazzling and radiating light of truth stands over against the shadowy darkness of evil, even a small child is capable of making a prudent and righteous choice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But for Christians, the path of faithfulness more often unwinds itself in long seasons of ordinariness, and in the small habits, the “second-nature” choices we make while we tackle the mundane matters of everyday living. Not once, but every morning, we rise to live as Christ’s disciples in this world. Not once, but every hour throughout the day, we listen—to scripture, to friends, to the witness of God’s Holy Spirit, to the inquisitiveness of our own minds—hoping to hear a living Word and seeking the Holy Spirit’s guidance, so that we may be more faithful. Not once, but every night, we lie down to rest ourselves trusting not in our righteousness, but in the saving grace of Jesus our Lord.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The true “heroes” of Christian discipleship are not made in a day, but daily. To ignore the opportunities for faithfulness in the little matters of everyday life is to ignore a very central part of Jesus teaching. When crisis times do come—times of spiritual harvest or judgment— they will not make a person suddenly righteous or unrighteous. They simply reveal who already is.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Big Changes at LIFT</title>
      <link>http://liftrenewal.org/blog/big-changes-at-lift</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Mar 2014 16:09:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <author>Jeremy Ricketts</author>
      <guid>http://liftrenewal.org/blog/big-changes-at-lift</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I can now share that my Bishop, Minerva Carcaño, has announced that she intends to appoint me as the Pastor of First United Methodist Church of Orange, effective July 1st, 2014.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The mantle of Executive Director has been passed to Dr. Bob Denham. Bob is a gifted lay leader, a valuable leader in his local church, and past California-Pacific Conference “Lay Person of the Year”. He most recently served as Dean of the Graduate School of Education at the University of Redlands, is very involved in Kairos Prison Ministries, and is a devoted man of prayer. I am pleased to announce that Judy Gillham (JGill) will continue her excellent work as Ministries Coordinator for LIFT. Words alone can never express the gift she brings to LIFT Ministries through keeping our standards of excellence high and our trust in Christ higher still. I will retain the title of General Evangelist/Founding Director of LIFT Ministries, and continue to relate to the Board of Directors and LIFT in that capacity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This has been an amazing 10 years, during which time a solid foundation has been laid that has opened doors for many fruitful ministry opportunities in the years to come. The grace of God and your prayers have brought LIFT Ministries this far, and we desire your continued prayers as LIFT moves forward so that we can build on that foundation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The earnest prayers you’ve raised on our behalf have often been all the support we’ve needed to move forward in service to Christ. Now, for the first time in 10 years, LIFT is encountering opportunities for ministry that will need temporal support as well from the Body of Christ. Therefore I’m asking, as Dr. Bob Denham assumes his duties, please pray for him, and about the ways you can support the ministries LIFT is trying to bless. You’ll be hearing more about projects in San Bernardino, Riverside, and Africa in the months to come.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To you who are such good friends of LIFT, may I say simply, “Thank-you.” Thank you for these past 10 years. Thank you for your prayers–I’ve felt them every single day. As we journey on together, I remain convinced that He who began a good work in us will carry it on to completion until the day of Christ Jesus. Amen.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Disciples are Sent to Bear Fruit</title>
      <link>http://liftrenewal.org/blog/disciples-are-sent-to-bear-fruit</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2013 16:10:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <author>Jeremy Ricketts</author>
      <guid>http://liftrenewal.org/blog/disciples-are-sent-to-bear-fruit</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Among the many Kingdom teachings of Jesus we find this jarring question: “why do you call me ‘Lord, Lord’ and do not do what I tell you?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the earliest of times the church has recognized that anyone can claim the name of Jesus, and make a pretense of calling themselves “Christian disciples,” but it is another matter altogether to share the heart of Christ and submit to his word. For though we are “saved by grace, through faith,” the nature of that faith is only truly revealed through one word: Obedience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To believe in Christ–to have faith in him–is to commit to his way, to submit to his truth, and to receive life from him on his terms. Faith is selling out, wholeheartedly, to the word and will of Christ Jesus our Lord, and to accept him alone as the foundation of our life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anything short of such radical obedience will never bear Kingdom fruit; as 19th century author and theologian George McDonald once said, “If we cannot think of a single time in our life when we did a thing because Jesus said ‘do that’ or withheld our hand because Jesus said ‘don’t do that’, then we have every reason to believe we are no disciple of his at all.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Claiming the name of Christ is not the same as taking up the cross and bearing it into the world. And yet, if we are careful to seek the will of Christ Jesus in every aspect of our lives–in small details and in heavy, consequential matters–then we find that the “burden” of bearing the cross is easy, and the yoke of Christ is light. Soon enough abundant fruit appears in our life, not because we seek the fruit, but because it pleases God to make us fruitful. In our daily obedience to Christ is the foundation for the Kingdom of God.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Almost There - Again</title>
      <link>http://liftrenewal.org/blog/almost-there-again</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Sep 2012 16:11:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <author>Jeremy Ricketts</author>
      <guid>http://liftrenewal.org/blog/almost-there-again</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;According to the Gospel of Mark, Jesus’ public ministry began when he appeared in Galilee proclaiming the good news, and from start to finish his urgent message remained the same: the time is fulfilled, and the Kingdom of God has come near. This good news was offered to everyone, without discrimination, and those who wanted to participate were freely invited to repent and believe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But while some indeed believed, not everyone took the invitation to heart. The reactions to Jesus and his ministry were apparently rich and varied. Many were filled with fear, awe and amazement, gratitude, loyalty, enthusiasm, and even a desire to worship. But others wrung their hands and were filled skepticism, anger, bewilderment, envy, and desire to have Jesus taken away as a blasphemer. It seems that no one was neutral on the subject of Jesus and his Kingdom!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It may seem odd that among the fiercest opposition to Jesus and his message were the most recognized religious leaders of that time, but the same is often true of “religious people” in our own time. Perhaps it’s because our greatest enemy in coming to Christ and his kingdom is our own pride, and the greatest hiding place for proud people is among the folds and trappings of religion. Did you hear our choir? Did you see how many we fed at our food bank last weekend? Did you hear that sermon…awesome! Do you know how many hours we put into the vacation bible school? Didn’t we provide just the boost the church needed in the last stewardship campaign? God must be so pleased with us…when it comes to building his kingdom, we’re almost there!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To be clear, religion itself is not the culprit. As Christians, our religious disciplines really do provide illumination and point the way toward life in Christ. But we must always remember that we don’t build God’s kingdom, we receive it. Our disciplines of faith are—like a bright moon in the night sky—a faithful reflection of the Light of the world. But religion is not the source of that light…merely it’s reflection. The kingdom of God is born anew in us as we forsake our own best practices, look beyond the trappings of religion, and encounter Christ himself. In that living, ongoing relationship, is life indeed.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Holy Week Confession</title>
      <link>http://liftrenewal.org/blog/holy-week-confession</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Apr 2012 16:13:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <author>Jeremy Ricketts</author>
      <guid>http://liftrenewal.org/blog/holy-week-confession</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The LORD said to Moses: “Speak to the Israelites, and tell them to make fringes on the corners of their garments throughout their generations and to put a blue cord on the fringe at each corner. You have the fringe so that, when you see it, you will remember all the commandments of the LORD and do them, and not follow the lust of your own heart and your own eyes. So you shall remember and do all my commandments, and you shall be holy to your God. I am the LORD your God, who brought you out of the land of Egypt, to be your God: I am the LORD your God.” - Numbers 15:37-41 -&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dominating the headlines last week was a multi-state lottery whose jackpot had swollen to two-thirds of a billion dollars. That’s billion, with a “B”. It seemed for a few days like nearly everyone was talking about it. People were joking together, daydreaming together, taking turns sharing their personal “what if?” or “why not?” in hushed and reverential tones while their eyes searched the horizon for a glimpse of how brightly lit the future would we if it were cloaked in all the robes of a lottery winner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the years I’ve preached dozens of sermons exhorting the church to steer away from gambling, but last week that didn’t stop me (and a couple of friends who will remain nameless) from joining in the “fun” and forming our own little conspiracy and buying a couple of tickets each. Not that we really serious about it. After all, to get a true picture of the odds of winning you’d have to fill the largest football stadium in the United States to capacity over 180 times and then pick out a single individual for the honor. But by last week enough tickets had been purchased to account for every possible combination of numbers. “Someone is going to win…why not us?” we joked. And what’s the harm? Financially I’ve spent more on a round of coffee for these same friends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is most often in small matters that we begin to stray from God. It seems relatively harmless to waste a few moments, or part of an afternoon, spinning fantasies of being other than we are and indulging ourselves in what author and neuroscientist Dr. Robert A. Burton calls “the pleasure of our thoughts.” (Burton, On Being Certain, Believing You Are Right Even When You’re Not, Pg. 86)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The trouble is, small things tend to add up quickly. From the time of Moses until now, one of the characteristic traits of God’s people has been that even when completely filled with God’s grace we tend to leak. We forget, dissipate, distract, set aside, and ignore the very things we are meant to do, and then fill up the little cracks and empty spaces with stuff we are really better off without. But when my hand reaches to take hold of anything other than what God wills for my life, it doesn’t really matter whether I’m clutching onto thirty little lottery numbers or thirty pieces of silver…when it separates me from the will of God, sin is still sin even in tiny and subtle forms. Small and insignificant indulgences, left unchecked, will grow like weeds and choke out the Holy Spirit’s work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No wonder Moses and the Israelites talked constantly about the laws of God. They meditated on them, they slept on them, they recalled them in “their going out and in their coming in”, they taught them diligently to their children, and when they still tended to forget they tied blue tassels onto the corners of their prayer shawls to help them remember: obedience to God is the source of their power and their life together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t usually cover my head when I pray, or gaze in meditation upon a blue-tasseled garment, but I have in Christ Jesus a living reminder and example of perfect obedience to the will of God. Reading through the scriptures in this Holy Week the Spirit speaks to my heart, and I look upon the image of a solitary man, God’s only begotten son, sacrificing his very self so that every other person may have life “in abundance.” I eat the bread and drink from the cup and receive life from one who gave himself for all. One, given for all! Is not the very shape of our communion the pure antithesis of gambling, where all have given (sometimes disastrously so) and only one will receive everything?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Almighty God, through your Son Jesus you have revealed to us the path and the example of love’s perfection. Grant us the strength and the grace to follow him in that way that brings life to the world. Heal our vision until we see nothing but your will, heal our hearts so that we may learn to love as you love, and strengthen our will with discipline that we may accomplish your purpose. Forgive us, cleanse us, and renew us by the power of your Holy spirit, through Jesus our Lord. Amen.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
