<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>LIFT Renewal Ministries</title>
    <link>http://liftrenewal.org</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jul 2016 16:22:38 -0700</pubDate>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lectionary Reading Week</title>
      <link>http://liftrenewal.org/events/lectionary-reading-week</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Sep 2016 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <author>Jeremy Ricketts</author>
      <guid>http://liftrenewal.org/events/lectionary-reading-week</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Spend a dedicated week with your colleagues in ministry reading through all the Gospel passages for the coming year, crafting a plan for your preaching ministry in the 2016-17 Lectionary Year. The Southern California session is moving this year to beautiful &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Oak Glen in the heart of Apple Country&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;! &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prayer Walk at University UMC</title>
      <link>http://liftrenewal.org/events/prayer-walk-at-university-umc</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Jul 2016 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <author>Jeremy Ricketts</author>
      <guid>http://liftrenewal.org/events/prayer-walk-at-university-umc</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Come join the LIFT Ministries Prayer Walk at University  United Methodist Church in Redlands - 9 A.M. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All are welcome! On the 2nd Saturday of each month we start out from a different church in the Inland Empire in order to cover our communities with Prayer, and Listen to God. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ll have a brief time of worship and prayer together,
then walk and pray silently through the community.&lt;br&gt;
Open to EVERYONE - you don&amp;rsquo;t need to be an expert &amp;lsquo;pray-er&amp;rsquo;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And this is the confidence that we have toward him, that if we ask anything according to his will he hears us. 1 John 5:14&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spoke &#39;N Word</title>
      <link>http://liftrenewal.org/events/spoke-n-word</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jul 2016 11:04:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <author>Jeremy Ricketts</author>
      <guid>http://liftrenewal.org/events/spoke-n-word</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Worship, Cycle, Eat - Repeat!
Coming this September, join up with a new cycling group which &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Seminar - The Ministry of the Church Office</title>
      <link>http://liftrenewal.org/events/ministry-of-the-church-office</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Feb 2016 09:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <author>Jeremy Ricketts</author>
      <guid>http://liftrenewal.org/events/ministry-of-the-church-office</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;LIFT Ministries&lt;/strong&gt; will once again present this Seminar designed to strengthen,encourage,and equip those persons entrusted with running the church office and assisting the Pastor &amp;ndash; &lt;strong&gt;Administrative Assistants, Office Managers, Church Secretaries&lt;/strong&gt;, etc. This is a very important ministry to which God calls us in order to use our spiritual gifts to their fullest to give glory to God and strengthen the Body of Christ.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ll spend a day away from the office to worship, and engage in prayer and Bible study together, then take a good look at the responsibilities and challenges of your job through the lens of Ministry.  Understanding that church administration is not merely a set of tasks on a job description, LIFT is offering an opportunity for participants to indeed embrace their roles as ministry,identify a variety of spiritual and practical resources available to them, and be renewed as they return to their workplace. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“The Ministry of the Church Office&amp;quot;&lt;/strong&gt; is facilitated by &lt;strong&gt;Judy Gillham&lt;/strong&gt;, herself a veteran of church office administration, and currently serves as the Ministries Coordinator for LIFT Ministries. She is a woman of deep prayer and great faith, who believes that we are charged with working “as unto the Lord” in all things. Judy brings experience, compassion, and her sense of humor to this seminar and is eager to share this special day with her colleagues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Contact St. Andrew UMC for more information, and to register. (805) 937-2470&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>God is God, and I am not. </title>
      <link>http://liftrenewal.org/blog/god-is-god-and-i-am-not</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2016 15:06:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <author>Jeremy Ricketts</author>
      <guid>http://liftrenewal.org/blog/god-is-god-and-i-am-not</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There is one simple rule of life which every Christian ought to hold in absolute acceptance:  &lt;em&gt;God is God, and I am not&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How wonderful it is, then, that God made us capable of worship. Human beings are made to sing, and praise, to meditate on holy things, and to bow down in worship before “holy mysteries.” All humans are capable of performing acts of worship, but we are called in Christ to offer worship exclusively to  the living God.  We are resolved that nothing else in heaven or on earth will have a place of reverence in our hearts. Likewise, the name of God is never to be used for gain, exploitation, or as a scapegoat for ungodly behavior,  and God’s name is never invoked casually or carelessly.  This is true not only on Sunday morning, but all the days in between; if we hold the name of God sacred above all other things, then we are bound to be his people in every aspect of our lives.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thus, “Hallowing the name of God” involves so much more than repetition of special words, or the practice of specific religious rites, or keeping abstinence from certain things. Making an outward show of things—pasting a cross on the top of our stationary or gluing a fish on the back of our car for instance—is of little or no value in and of itself.  For it is inwardly, and spiritually, that we first learn to “hallow God’s name.”  Through our commitment to love the Lord with all our heart, mind, soul and strength, we practice yielding to Christ in all things, praying that through our surrendered obedience God’s love might be revealed to a hungry and hurting world in precisely the way that Jesus shares it with us: humbly, generously, sacrificially, and without price.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Such a commitment will change us over time. More and more the image of Christ will emerge in us as we receive grace through the Holy Spirit, hallow God’s name in our worship.  Over the span of a lifetime, the careful shaping of our will toward God’s heavenly purpose creates new pathways for the Gospel wherever our lives touch the world. The Kingdom of God comes to us in Christ, and then by God’s grace comes through us to touch God’s creation. As one dear saint remarked toward the end of her life on this earth, “all these years I’d supposed I was the one coming to church to make my prayers&amp;hellip;only recently have I discovered it was these prayers that were making me.”  So may it be for all who are pure in heart!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Abide</title>
      <link>http://liftrenewal.org/blog/abide</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2016 15:01:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <author>Jeremy Ricketts</author>
      <guid>http://liftrenewal.org/blog/abide</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I am the true vine&lt;/em&gt;&amp;hellip;.Jesus often used the simplest words and images to communicate the deepest truths of God’s love for us.  In John 15 are some of the last words Jesus spoke to his disciples before he was betrayed, arrested and crucified.  They were words of invitation and hope, of deep communion and lasting relationships, of painful “pruning” that blossoms into bountiful fruitfulness.  They were, on a very dark night, words of light and love.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Abide in me as I abide in you&lt;/em&gt;&amp;hellip;The call to “abide,” or remain, in Christ can be seen as a word of reassurance and promise to the church.  It brings reassurance because it illuminates Christ’s faithfulness toward the church—no matter what happens next he will continue to abide with us.  It also brings the promise of communion with God that will result in fruitful, bountiful, even joyful lives.   &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some may be tempted to ask How can I bear sure I will bear fruit?  What part of my life will have to be pruned? Will I miss the things that are taken away?  When will I know if I’m doing it right?  The word of Christ to these questions is simple and clear: abide in me.  As long as a branch remains in the vine, fruit will appear in season.  For it is the vine that produces the fruit, and the branch that bears it forth to the world.  Branches do not conjure their own fruit, nor can Christians produce anything of their own. God produces fruit in us, and we bring it forth to God’s glory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Christian faith is an exercise in abiding&amp;hellip;it is a living relationship.  Not once in a lifetime, but every morning, we rise to live as Christ’s disciples in this world.  Not once, but every hour throughout the day, we listen—to scripture, to friends, to the witness of God’s Holy Spirit, to the inquisitiveness of our own minds—hoping to hear a living Word and seeking the Holy Spirit’s guidance, so that we may be more faithful.  Not once, but every night, we lie down to rest ourselves trusting not in our righteousness, but in the saving grace of Jesus our Lord.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abiding in Christ is as natural as a plant soaking up water from the soil, or basking in sunlight on a pleasant afternoon. It can be as easy as breathing in and breathing out&amp;hellip;all the while submitting to a faithful God, who cleanses us in order to draw us closer in.  &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Discipleship-Personal, but never Private</title>
      <link>http://liftrenewal.org/blog/discipleship-personal-but-never-private</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2016 14:58:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <author>Jeremy Ricketts</author>
      <guid>http://liftrenewal.org/blog/discipleship-personal-but-never-private</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;In Praise of Jesus Christ:  The Foundation of Our Work and Witness&amp;rdquo; 1 Peter 2:4-10&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Becoming a disciple of Christ is a deeply personal experience&amp;hellip;but it is never private.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Christ we have become part of a body, and are incorporated into his mighty acts of salvation for the whole world.  Individual Christians experience salvation as a breathtaking passage from darkness to light, or a hard and painful squeeze through a gate so narrow that no else could fit.  But when each new Christian comes gasping and blinking into the dazzling brilliance of God&amp;rsquo;s Kingdom, the first thing he or she sees is a countless multitude of other Christians, each one likewise bedazzled by the experience of coming through a gateway just large enough for themselves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The author of 1 Peter exhorts the church to come to Christ&amp;ndash;who is himself a living stone&amp;ndash;and &amp;ldquo;like living stones let ourselves be built&amp;rdquo; into a temple of sacrifice and praise.  It is a call from from an individualistic, &amp;ldquo;Lone Ranger&amp;rdquo; approach to ministry and into koinonia&amp;ndash;fellowship in the Holy Spirit.  The Greek word for &amp;ldquo;building&amp;rdquo; here is rendered in a passive tense, forever reminding the church that it is Christ Jesus alone who is building his church, and our task is to &amp;ldquo;simply&amp;rdquo; to make our lives available for his purpose and pleasure.   &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some Christians say “act a certain way and the heart will follow.”  Others say “fix the heart first, and then right actions will come around.”   In the end, both approaches are true; for from top to bottom, from outside to inside, from heart to highway, we are wholly  and dearly loved by God.  As we follow Christ faithfully, and as we submit to him in all things, we become &amp;ldquo;a people set apart&amp;rdquo; by him&amp;hellip;a chosen race&amp;hellip;a royal priesthood.   In Christ&amp;rsquo;s love you and I are becoming &amp;ldquo;we&amp;rdquo; together, and the watching world &amp;ldquo;sees our good works, and gives glory to our Father in Heaven.&amp;rdquo;  May it ever be so.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LIFT Renewal Weekend</title>
      <link>http://liftrenewal.org/events/lift-renewal-weekend-hemet</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jan 2016 14:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <author>Jeremy Ricketts</author>
      <guid>http://liftrenewal.org/events/lift-renewal-weekend-hemet</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In January, Hemet UMC hosts a 3-Day Renewal weekend that will feature meaningful worship and prayer, in-depth Bible study, retreat-time for church leaders and staff, and warm Christian fellowship, all focusing on drawing closer to the heart of God and deepening their discipleship to Jesus Christ. &lt;strong&gt;Worship every evening at 7pm&lt;/strong&gt; The preacher for the Weekend is the Rev. Bill Johnson.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Christmas Open House</title>
      <link>http://liftrenewal.org/events/christmas-open-house</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Dec 2015 14:29:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <author>Jeremy Ricketts</author>
      <guid>http://liftrenewal.org/events/christmas-open-house</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Come enjoy warm fellowship and holiday treats at the &lt;strong&gt;Annual Christmas Open House&lt;/strong&gt; at the LIFT Offices. &lt;strong&gt;1:00 pm to 5:00 pm.&lt;/strong&gt; Everyone is welcome! LIFT is located in Uptown Whittier, between Philadelphia &amp;amp; Bailey. Offices are upstairs (no elevator). &lt;em&gt;Hope to see YOU there!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prayer Walking</title>
      <link>http://liftrenewal.org/events/prayer-walking-nov-14-1</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Nov 2015 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <author>Jeremy Ricketts</author>
      <guid>http://liftrenewal.org/events/prayer-walking-nov-14-1</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Cover the Inland Empire with Prayer&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Every 2nd Saturday of the month&lt;/em&gt;, LIFT Ministries goes Prayer Walking in the community surrounding the church. There is time for worship and prayer together, then, in small groups, we walk through the neighborhood to listen to God and lift up the community in prayer. Come be a blessing. Come bring light and peace into the world!See you at EMMANUEL UMC in San Bernardino! &lt;strong&gt;Gather at 9am in the Sanctuary.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prayer Walking-Nov. 14</title>
      <link>http://liftrenewal.org/events/prayer-walking-nov-14</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Oct 2015 09:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <author>Jeremy Ricketts</author>
      <guid>http://liftrenewal.org/events/prayer-walking-nov-14</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Cover the Inland Empire with Prayer&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Every 2nd Saturday of the month&lt;/em&gt;, LIFT Ministries goes Prayer Walking in the community surrounding the church. There is time for worship and prayer together, then, in small groups, we walk through the neighborhood to listen to God and lift up the community in prayer. Come be a blessing. Come bring light and peace into the world!  See you at EMMANUEL UMC in San Bernardino! Gather at 9am in the Sanctuary.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clergy Class Meetings for September</title>
      <link>http://liftrenewal.org/events/clergy-class-meetings-september-2015</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2015 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <author>Jeremy Ricketts</author>
      <guid>http://liftrenewal.org/events/clergy-class-meetings-september-2015</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Every Wednesday morning at 10:30am, Pastors from churches in the Inland Empire gather for a traditional &lt;strong&gt;Wesleyan Class Meeting&lt;/strong&gt;. SEPTEMBER Class Meetings ALL clergy are welcome. Location changes monthly. Contact LIFT for more information. (562)789-0880&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ministry in Ghana</title>
      <link>http://liftrenewal.org/events/ministry-in-ghana</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Aug 2015 11:08:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <author>Jeremy Ricketts</author>
      <guid>http://liftrenewal.org/events/ministry-in-ghana</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A Team of 6 clergy and laypersons will travel to Accra, Ghana, in West Africa, this summer for a third mission trip to strengthen local church leaders in disciple-making. Your prayers are welcomed as they travel and serve! &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The past 2 years have focused on the &amp;ldquo;Big 5&amp;rdquo; of discipleship and building a Discipling Network which reaches out beyond the walls of the church. Following up on those previous seminars, LIFT this year will have conversation with a core group of leaders to encourage them forward in their efforts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;LIFT Team members will also take part in evening Revival Worship services and preach in local congregations on Sunday morning. A visit to the &lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;LIFT Renewal Center&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt; currently under construction will be included, to view the progress of this special project and pray with the construction team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;The LIFT Mission Team members:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rev. William Johnson &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dr. Bob Denham &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rev. Tonya Harris &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rev. Tom Rothhaar &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;David Nesamony &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Judy Gillham &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mission dates are: August 11 through 22, 2015.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your support for this work is greatly appreciated!  Prayer sustains the Team, and financial support helps with the cost of supplies. There is also an opportunity to support the building of the LIFT Renewal Center. By clicking on the &lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;Donate&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt; button you may make a gift to LIFT Ministries, and indicate how you would like your gift to be applied.  Thank-You! &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;Thou shalt decree a thing, and it shall be established unto thee; and the light shall shine upon thy ways.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;   Job 22:28&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a Place for Renewal</title>
      <link>http://liftrenewal.org/blog/building-a-place-for-renewal</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jun 2015 16:30:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <author>Jeremy Ricketts</author>
      <guid>http://liftrenewal.org/blog/building-a-place-for-renewal</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;LIFT Ministries&lt;/strong&gt;, in partnership with LIFT in Ghana, is supporting the creation of the &lt;strong&gt;LIFT Renewal Center&lt;/strong&gt;! &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Imagine&amp;hellip;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A place for Spiritual Retreat&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A place for Leadership Training&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A place for Visiting Missionaries&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A place to host the Walk to Emmaus&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the U.S. we are blessed with the availability of 
comfortable, affordable facilities. 
But the Methodist Church in Ghana has very limited facilities for pastors and laypersons to take retreat 
for spiritual renewal,apart from expensive hotels.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Together we can make this happen - We are blessed to be a blessing!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;LIFT Ministries is raising money in order to build this facility 
which will be used for all these purposes as well 
as hosting Walk to Emmaus weekends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thus far, LIFT has raised $11,000 to build the Center ! 
The remaining cost to complete the construction 
is approximately $60,000.
You can support this vital project by making a 
tax-deductible gift to LIFT Ministries in any amount.   &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Visit &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.LiftRenewal.org&quot;&gt;www.LiftRenewal.org&lt;/a&gt; and click &amp;ldquo;Donate&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Thank-You!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Renewal Center in Ghana</title>
      <link>http://liftrenewal.org/events/renewal-center-in-ghana</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jun 2015 12:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <author>Jeremy Ricketts</author>
      <guid>http://liftrenewal.org/events/renewal-center-in-ghana</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;LIFT Ministries&lt;/strong&gt;, in partnership with LIFT in Ghana,is supporting the creation of the &lt;strong&gt;LIFT Renewal Center&lt;/strong&gt;! &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Imagine&amp;hellip;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A place for Spiritual Retreat&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A place for Leadership Training&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A place for Visiting Missionaries&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A place to host the Walk to Emmaus&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the U.S. we are blessed with the availability of 
comfortable, affordable facilities. 
But the Methodist Church in Ghana has very limited facilities for pastors and laypersons to take retreat 
for spiritual renewal,apart from expensive hotels.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Together we can make this happen - We are blessed to be a blessing!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;LIFT Ministries is raising money in order to build this facility 
which will be used for all these purposes as well 
as hosting Walk to Emmaus weekends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thus far, LIFT has raised $5,000 to build the Center ! 
The remaining cost to complete the construction 
is approximately $60,000.
You can support this vital project by making a 
tax-deductible gift to LIFT Ministries in any amount.   &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Visit &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.LiftRenewal.org&quot;&gt;www.LiftRenewal.org&lt;/a&gt; and click &amp;ldquo;Donate&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Thank-You!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LIFT Renewal Weekend</title>
      <link>http://liftrenewal.org/events/lift-renewal-weekend</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 May 2015 14:11:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <author>Jeremy Ricketts</author>
      <guid>http://liftrenewal.org/events/lift-renewal-weekend</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prayer Walking</title>
      <link>http://liftrenewal.org/events/prayer-walking-9-12-2015</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Apr 2015 09:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <author>Jeremy Ricketts</author>
      <guid>http://liftrenewal.org/events/prayer-walking-9-12-2015</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Cover the Inland Empire with Prayer&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Every 2nd Saturday of the month&lt;/em&gt;, LIFT Ministries goes Prayer Walking in the community surrounding the church. There is time for worship and prayer together, then, in small groups, we walk through the neighborhood to listen to God and lift up the community in prayer. Come be a blessing. Come bring light and peace into the world!  See you at HIGHLAND UMC in San Bernardino! Gather at 9am in the Sanctuary.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Board of Directors Annual Meeting</title>
      <link>http://liftrenewal.org/events/board-of-directors-annual-meeting</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Mar 2015 09:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <author>Jeremy Ricketts</author>
      <guid>http://liftrenewal.org/events/board-of-directors-annual-meeting</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Board of Directors of LIFT Renewal Ministries will gather for their Annual Meeting at the LIFT Offices in Uptown Whittier.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ghana Mission Meeting</title>
      <link>http://liftrenewal.org/events/ghana-mission-meeting</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Mar 2015 10:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <author>Jeremy Ricketts</author>
      <guid>http://liftrenewal.org/events/ghana-mission-meeting</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;By God&amp;rsquo;s grace, LIFT will again organize a Team to serve in Ghana this summer. If you would like to learn about this mission and be considered for the Team, you&amp;rsquo;re invited to attend an information meeting at the LIFT Ministries office on &lt;strong&gt;Saturday, March 7th at 10am.&lt;/strong&gt;. If you have any questions ahead of time, please call Judy Gillham, Ministry Coordinator, at &lt;strong&gt;(562) 789-0880, or click the &amp;ldquo;Contact&amp;rdquo; tab to email LIFT&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inland Empire Prayer Walking</title>
      <link>http://liftrenewal.org/events/inland-empire-prayer-walking</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2015 09:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <author>Jeremy Ricketts</author>
      <guid>http://liftrenewal.org/events/inland-empire-prayer-walking</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Saturday - February 14 - is the next LIFT Prayer Walk in the St. Paul&amp;rsquo;s United Methodist Church in San Bernardino. On the 2nd Saturday of each month we start out from a different church in the Inland Empire area in order to cover our communities with Prayer and Listen to God.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All are welcome! Meet at St. Paul&amp;rsquo;s UMC at 9am. We’ll have a brief time of worship and prayer together, then form small groups to walk and pray silently through the community. A couple people will be asked to remain in the Sanctuary to keep vigil while we walk, interceding for the walkers. After about 45 minutes or so, we’ll return to the church to share what God was showing us, then pray, and return home. Come and be a blessing in the community!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And this is the confidence that we have toward him, that if we ask anything according to his will he hears us. 1 John 5:14&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
